A Guide to the Spelman Fund of New York records FA063
Rockefeller Archive Center
- General Files, 1922-1945; 5
  - Pan-American Congress of Municipalities, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 784)
  - Pan-American Congress of Municipalities - Dossier (Box 4, Folder 785)
  - Pan-American Congress of Municipalities - Reports (Box 4, Folder 786)
  - President's Emergency Committee for Unemployment, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 787)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Projects, 1929-1944 (Box 4, Folder 788)
  - Rosenwald Fund, 1929-1936 (Box 4, Folder 789)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1929-1932 (Box 4, Folder 790)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 791)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1936-1941 (Box 5, Folder 792)
  - Social Science Research Council - Reports (Box 5, Folder 793)
  - Social Science Research Council - Reports (Box 5, Folder 794)
  - Social Science Research Council - Reports (Box 5, Folder 795)
  - Social Security Board, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 796)
  - Syracuse University - School of Citizenship and Public Affairs, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 797)
  - United States Civil Service Commission, 1931-1939 (Box 5, Folder 798)
  - United States Department of Agriculture, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 799)
  - United States Department of Agriculture - Personnel, 1938-1940 (Box 5, Folder 800)
  - United States Department of Interior, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 801)
  - United States Department of Labor, 1933-1939 (Box 5, Folder 802)
  - University of Minnesota - Parents Publishing Association (Box 5, Folder 803)
  - University of Toronto - Child Study, 1929-1932 (Box 5, Folder 804)
  - University of Virginia - Bureau of Public Administration, 1936-1941 (Box 6, Folder 805)
  - University of Chicago, 1938-1941 (Box 6, Folder 806)
  - University of Southern California, 1930-1936 (Box 6, Folder 807)
  - White, Leonard, 1933-1935 (Box 6, Folder 808)
  - Miscellaneous (A-Z) (Box 6, Folder 809)
  - Miscellaneous (A-Z) (Box 6, Folder 810)
  - Miscellaneous (A-Z) (Box 6, Folder 811)
  - Miscellaneous (A-Z) (Box 6, Folder 812)
  - Miscellaneous (A-Z) (Box 6, Folder 813)
  - Miscellaneous (A-Z) (Box 6, Folder 814)
- Spelman Fund of New York photographs, 1934-1957; 1015; 0.1 Cubic Feet; 11 prints
  Biographical / Historical
  The Spelman Fund of New York was chartered as a corporation on December 27, 1928, exclusively for "charitable, scientific and educational purposes including the advancement and diffusion of knowledge concerning child life, the improvement of interracial relations and cooperation with public agencies."
  $10,000,000 was provided for The Spelman Fund by the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial shortly after the latter organization merged with The Rockefeller Foundation in 1929. The Memorial had developed a broad program in child study and interracial relations. Though the Fund continued to support some of the agencies previously supported by the Memorial for the duration of the particular grant, the main program of the Fund was in the area of public administration and intergovernmental relations. This was an area the Memorial had just begun to develop in its program, and it soon became the primary interest of the Fund. The Fund worked to improve the technical aspects of public administration. They supported activities which would improve exchange of technical information and experience and also activities of research to discover improved methods and techniques of organization.
  Many major appropriations were made to the "1313" agencies, i.e., the American Association of Public Welfare Officials, the American Legislators Association, the American Municipal Association, the American Public Welfare Association, the American Public Works Association, the American Society of Planning Officials, the Civil Service Assembly, the Council of State Governments, the Federation of Tax Administrators, the International City Managers Association, the Municipal Financial Officers Association, the National Association of Housing Officials, the Public Administration Clearing House and the Public Administration Service. These groups were brought together in Chicago in 1932, and later in a building on the campus of the University of Chicago. The address was 1313 E. 60th Street, hence the name.
  The final grant of unexpended funds was made to the Public Administration Clearing House, the nerve center of the "1313" agencies, and in 1949 the Fund was dissolved.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Photographs, slides, and other images are open for scholarly research.
  Photographs
  - Spelman Fund of New York, 1934-1957; Some mounted on board, captions on back, 2 fading; 1 folder; 11 prints (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Buildings, construction, conferences, staff.